Zeljko Dakic

Overview

Heroic greatness

I am an accomplished software engineer with more than 10 years of experience on high-profile projects, looking for leadership role to engineer project success.

Technical Skills

Awesome excellence

Apply methodologies: Agile (Scrum and XP), Test Driven Development, System Analysis, Full Lifecycle Development, Object-Oriented Design and Development

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, CoffeeScript, PHP, dabble in Elixir, ClojureScript etc

Internet Development: Rails, Node.js, Backbone, AngularJS, Meteor, Laravel

UI: jQuery, Zurb Foundation, Bootstrap, Haml, Slim, UIKit...

Manage & Model Databases: MySQL, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Neo4j, RethinkDB

Testing: RSpec, Cucumber, Factory Girl, Capybara, Selenium, Jasmine, Watir

Experience

Sublime transcendence

Lead Developer, ParkWhiz, Chicago (Sep 2014-Current)

- Coordinate work with consulting team and provide support and guidance
- Implement good practices like continous integration and code coverage
- Implement api using engines

Process: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile

Lead Developer, Enova, Chicago (May 2014-Sep 2014)

- Coordinate work with offshore team and provide support and guidance
- Work as developer on Canada and Australia team
- Improve test suite

Process: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile

Lead Developer, FitStudio/Sears Holdings, Chicago (Dec 2011-Apr 2014)

- Plan, develop and maintain fitstudio.com
- Work as lead on searsstyle.com and part of kenmoreconnect.com team
- Coordinate work with offshore team and provide support and guidance

Process: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile, Neo 4j, Mongo DB, Sass

Senior Developer, BenchPrep, Chicago (Apr 2011-Sept 2011)

- Work on BenchPrep main product, implemented discussion feature
- Introduced integration testing using Cucumber/Selenium

Process: Ruby on Rails, Backbone, CoffeeScript, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile

Software Developer & Consultant, Obtiva/Groupon, Chicago (Jul 2010-Apr 2011)

- Worked on key new features like merchant self service center
- Internal tools, involved in performance tuning initiatives.
- Created map visualisation of subscriber distribution for deal targeting

Process: Ruby on Rails, TDD, RSpec, Cucumber, Resque, Haml, Sass

Developer & Frontend Lead, Obtiva/ManageMyHome.com, Chicago (Jul 2009-Jun 2010)

• ManageMyHome.com I was working on front-end and lead front end team in number of initiatives to bring standard based design, refactor and implement best practices

Process: Ruby on Rails, TDD, Scrum, RSpec, Cucumber, Selenium, Git, jQuery, Jasmine

Software Developer & Consultant, Dakic OnLine, Chicago (Jun 2008-Jul 2009)

Notable Projects:

- DeviKroell.com rewrite site in code igniter, developed backend and added a lot of jQuery for usability
- WinifredGrace.com recreating ecommerce site, used Magento for ecommerce engine, Blueprint css framework and jQuery for javascript. Wrote slideshows, scrollers and gallery browsers for content pages using jQuery.
- 3+ years doing confidential work for Dream Marketing, worked on more then 20 sites with asp.net and ms sql server, mostly development work with some smaller styling and special javascript.
- LutzandPatmos.com, developed ecommerce presence using magento, worked with designer on front-end, developed theme and worked on css and jscript on content pages.

Software Architect, ShopJake.com, Chicago (Jun 2007-Mar 2008)

- Re-created website core and checkout using CodeIgniter MVC framework
- Integrated website with third-party services for mailing lists, payment processing
- Made other improvements and changes

Process: PHP, MVC, CodeIgniter. Rails

Lead Developer & Consultant, Zocalo Group, Chicago (Jan 2006-Nov 2007)

- Continued development of RevereNet under new name ZocaloNet and branding.
- Upgraded application to version of Rails 1.2.3 and started move to Rails 2.0 features
- Added number of enhancements, usability improvements
- Developed number of new features to bring the application to version 2.0

Process: Ruby on Rails, Eclipse, Subversion, Ajax, Agile

Affiliations

Social Network

Ruby User Group, Javascript User Group Chicago FONDIP—Alumni Organization SETNet—Founder of South European Team Network

Education *Important*

2001, B.S., Business Administration, Major: Management Information Systems University of Belgrade, Serbia